so thanks everyone for joining this talk
especially Hui Ming
cause he is giving me this opportunity to share here
cause before that I'm playing AI with my teams
and then we
not sure
whether we are going to the right track or not
so he give me this opportunity
here to share about my knowledge
in AI so at least I can gather some feedback or what
so I can know whether or not we are on the right track
so today I'm going to share my company AI journey
so my title is from manual coding to chat
ChatGPT, Cursor and Claude Code yeah okay
so let's start so something about me
so my name is Kowa Jia Liang
my surname is Kowa and I'm a senior software engineer
working in Singapore
my company name is Payboy Private Limited
it's not Playboy, we do HRMS SaaS product
it's like human resource things
so we helping companies handling like payrolls
leave attendance taxes etcetera
so we mainly use Ruby on Rails for back end and Vue
JS for front end so
my day to day task will be mostly on planning
task with my project manager
and then also reviewing PR right
so let's get start
so this is our evolution of AI in our workspace
so first definitely we are all on manual coding
like traditional syntax typing
browsing documentation StackOverflow for solutions
then after that we go to prompting like ChatGPT
so ChatGPT is like we copy and paste
code fragments to webchat for opinion and answers ya
but it's very fast bit
but it's totally context blindness
every time we need to re explain what we want
and what is our product logic
so it's very time consuming ya
then after that we go to cursor IDE
so we finally have an AI agent sit inside IDE
so it gives us fast response
indexing files and auto complete recommendation
like Copilot like the Tab thing ya
then lastly we go to VS Code plus Claude
which is our currently using 1
so this is very similar to Claude but a bit different
it has different background agent
looping and running checks
tasks and diagnostics locally
so this one I'll share later in later slides
alright okay
next so different era
this one is just like supporting the previous slide
so we have two different AI
so first is like browser era
like is like the ChatGPT
like
we keep copying and switching windows to get solutions
like they have no context
requires manual describing model
every time I need to describe what is my product
logic
then I need to keep repeating the same thing
then it's very troublesome for me
then after that we have this editor native AI
so he sit within our editor
so with this we have no more copy and paste
switching browser
it just live directly inside my workspace
to read and write my files ya
so he have awareness
so means that he have background indexing of files
utilities and my code styling standards
so we don't need to repeat what we using like
what library we using
what code structure we expecting
so we don't need to repeat all these things
they already know what we need ya
so every time I prompt my agent right
so he already know what I'm expecting
so I don't need to keep repeating
I don't want this I don't want that change that format
ya so this is the good of the editor AI
so
how we use Claude Code to improve our team performance
right so we have these three main things
so we automate processes with Claude Code
first thing is we have permanent context
so it's a markdown file inside my project repo
so it's a file that step is storing standardized
active tech stack for my project
like my build with sequence testing parameters
styling rules and what gem we use
what library we use
and it's placed directly at the project root
so whenever I start my ID right
so he already loads all the rules from my markdown file
ya so when I start chat chatting with my agent
everything right
he already know what we expecting ya
so this is the permanent context
so next with Claude we can create custom skills
so we can create custom repository
workflow inside the Claude skills
repository is something coming with Claude 1
ya so we can trigger instantly
via sidebar slash command for example
changelog this one ya
then lastly is MCP like what Jun Wei showed just now
it's something like a USB-C for AI apps
so it just like a tools that you can connect
then you don't need to configure yourself
ya
so this one I will show some example later also
this one I have some proof of concept already
but I haven't got chance to set up yet ya
but maybe I will share some
like the proof of concept
ya so let me proceed
so first thing this is the permanent context
so this is the initial file that placed in my project
root
which it will auto loads whenever the IDE is loaded up
so I also call it as knowledge
so it's easier for us to understand among our team yeah
as you can see there's a lot of hashes here
so all these hashes right
they are act like a header
then we specify our requirement like apps overview
logic code structure and more within them
so you can see here I have like project architecture
front end architecture
then how many portals we have for our apps
then our code review checklist
all this I can specify here
this is a very huge file ya
so with this file right
then they already know before I start prompting them
so they know what I expecting ya
then go next this is my second thing is a custom skill
so you can see here this one is the Claude one
so I have a skills repo here
so all these are my custom skills for my repository
so you see here
each repo right as you can see here
this is like ai-agents, attendance, changelog, claims
these are like maybe my knowledge or it
it's something like a skill
I can trigger it for something
ask him to help me do something
or maybe I put some product knowledge in
so that he can know whenever I touch something
similar to this one
so he can retrieve the product logic here from here
this is my logic clocking out hours
calculation overtime requirements
something like that
so this feature is storing my knowledge
so it's like something like my product
no product logic
so whenever I trigger something related to attendance
right then he will like on self-check
whether he need like something like this
some product logic here
then we go on self retrieve the data
so he can know before I when he's doing some tasks
then he will on self go retrieve the data here
ya but this one is optional cause this one
for skill is like SKILL.md is a must
SKILL.md sits within the skill
it within the attendance
then feature is another repo inside attendance
so skill is a must skill is like something like
describing what is this attendance doing
and when we should trigger this skill right
then she inside here feature is the product logics
yup then I go next
then I will give some case study for custom skills
k so first thing is changelog
so for our team we do changelog
to record down what we did for each PR
that get merged into staging
and sometimes it's like
quite hard to summarize what we did for our PR
like for example
I fix a bug but I need to think like
what is the bug and how to describe
sometimes it's just like
consuming to log this thing down
so to solve this issue
I just created this change log skill
so what does this do right
is actually after I trigger agent will read my changes
current branch versus the target branch
then he will help me to summarize what I have done
so I can skip thinking like
what need to be logged down into changelog
then spending minutes to do this
then I just give him few seconds
he done already
then it will list down like what module I touch
the reason of these changes and what is the impact
etcetera so I can add in more things like Jira
card link or GitScrum card or whatever you like
for me I only add the PR link here
so as you can see here so he label this one as a fix
my PR is a fix then what I fix
this is the module
then he will list down everything
then together with like reason and impact
so what's my reason why I fixing this one
and what's the impact so this is my first custom skill
okay then second is called code-auditor skills
this one is my favourite
'cause okay
so for me
because I'm in charge of doing PR review for my teams
so I've been always repeating the same commands
so same comments to the devs
so instead of keep repeating the same comments right
I came up with this skill code-auditor
so what it does right
is to help me to run a pre PR review
so I ask my devs to run this skill
before they send to me for actual PR review
and with this
it wipes out a lot of redundant comments for me
so I need only need to review on the actual logic side
with which it saves save me a lot of times
so let me show you all how this work okay
so code-auditor right
actually he separate into like 3 main step
so first step is gather context
so code-auditor will request agent to ask the user
so like which branch you want to compare with default
I set to staging
our main branch
but we also can input like other branch to proceed
so second is after I getting the context
then I will run the actual PR review as per my corp
auditor rules also whatever modules you updated right
it will also trigger the related skills
the knowledge
which is the one I show you all just now
the first custom this the permanent context ya
so
to make sure AI understand the product logic correctly
so they can give valid and correct inputs
then after that right
step 3 is after review done
it will output a markdown file with all the concerns
label from critical important and suggestion
it will also list down the concern
come up with suggested solutions to
so before I do actual PR review right
the skill help me to eliminate 70 to 80%
of redundant comments already ya
so I will show you all some like
example that I run in the PR
yeah so wait
k right so this right hand side is my Claude Code
so I ran it yesterday
so I can show here yeah
wait let me try
can k wait right
so after I run this code-auditor right
then he will just run all these assert things
then after that ya okay
so based reserved to here is he asking me question
like which branch I want to compare with
so I choose production
cause I want to merge this directly to production
then he will start gathering the difference
between my branch and production branch
so you can see all these are he on self run one
like based on my rules
then he run all these thing like
cause this is a quite big PR
so he did a lot get diff
and do a sort to check whether or not I
like to check what changes I made
then after that right
this is the output in a markdown file so called audit
then he will list down like what's my source
this is my current branch versus the production branch
then what the PR does
then this is the summary then coverage
then he will list down like critical
issue that he think must fix before merge
then he will he will list down the following the cost
the fix then he will label important
the one he thinks should fix
and then like maybe suggestion
some nice to have and what's the strength of this PR
so all this thing he definitely
we still I still need to like
filter out what is the valid concerns yeah
but this one
he already help me to eliminate a lot of things already
cause I have this wait
let me show you all the yeah
this is my markdown file for the rules
it's a big file so I insert all my concerns here
so like what are the steps
what they need to do and what are the rules here
so it's a very big file
but this one is not come up by me
it's just I input what I want
so he wrote this file for me
like what they need to check what they need to do
yup so all this thing is written by AI
but it helps me a lot yes
a very big file so this is a code-auditor
yup okay so let me go next right
okay so that one is superpower parking so superpower
so whenever our team trying to do a new feature right
normally we will use this
open source call superpower plug in
so superpower is a software development methodology
for AI for coding agent
it's a public repo on GitHub one yeah
so how does this superpower work right
is whenever you trigger this superpower
first you digest your requirement from chat
then they will give you a proposal
or we can say is a coding plan with details
like what files you will be creating
according to your coding standard rules
come up with core logic functions
with test cases in the markdown file ya
so after you review the markdown file right
you can check and make any changes you want
then finally you sign off to green
to give green light to agent and proceed lastly
client will follow the markdown file
to start coding and design
then Claude will correct
parallel agents to test the written code
fix bug test and report repeat until all good ya
so all these
he speak into like different agent in background
and do the work parallelly
so I will give you an example of what I
1 of the project I use superpower to complete okay
so example in my company system
we have a back end control
system for our data's like
we always wanted to do a report
page to know what is our MRR also
you search for each module per month
per year because we are a SaaS product
but due to
we really no time to invest into this because
it's a report only no money is coming in mah
so the project was delayed for months
so after that I use this superpower and prompt
so this is my prompt refer to this GitHub
help me to create something similar
in my back end control system page
also I want a report for each of my modules
this my problem
then he start planning for around 8 to 10 minutes
and he back to back checking with me
what are the requirements
for this feature after that
right after he confirm everything
it took around 15 minutes to finish the feature
so I can show you all this PR so wait ya
so this one wait
so he this is created by I have this branch
but all these commits
right are created by this superpower
as you can see here is co-authored
yeah, it's Claude
so all these thing he following my
the markdown file that he design
and he create all these in
within 30 minutes yeah
for me it's definitely impossible
yeah and what are the good things right
is he come together with the test cases in my repo ya
so I totally don't need to care everything about this
ya and then this is the plan for superpower
after I using this one right
so this is his plan for this project
so you can see what he is showing
what is the file structure
what are the new files he will be creating
so he list down everything
what he will be modifying navigation notes
then what is his task sequence
all these thing he list down here until you sign off
so that he will start working on this project
so here are all the tasks
then the calculator for MRR
everything is listed here ya
even the queries he will ask for my opinion
how I want to query the DB for results yeah
so yup this is a superpower hmm
yes it's a huge file like over thousand of lines
so to me we use this quite often
because it's good to come up with something first
like for example you are given a feature
so to me I always use this one first to come up
at least prototype cause I
I'm not a front end person
so my frontend is
no sorry
say that my frontend is not good yeah
then I can fix from the implementation to avoid
a lot easier job like front end UI
cause I'm not a front end guy ya
so ya this is what he gave me in like 30 minutes
so it's a report page
each of the activity for my each of my modules
what are the count here
then he also come with the filters
then also the MRR revenue page
all these are done within like 30 minutes
with this superpower plug in ya okay
so let me go next so next is MCP tools okay
so MCP is a standardized interface for AI agent
so we can use MCP
to connect to various of data sources and tools
enabling the data to
enabling the AI to retrieve or post data easily
so the old way before MCP
we always need to create our custom API
code for every external connection
and it's very fragile cause
the in integration is easily broke
break whenever the tool API structure change ya
so this is very cause we
I never did this
cause this is very hard to maintain but now after MCP
right
so just one port expose the tools capability natively
directly inside Claude
so Claude can connects to a lot other applications
as long as they have this MCP
for us to connect the tools
so I just I don't need com
I don't need to do any integration or what
I just easy set up through JSON
B files only
cause they already have available gems and library yeah
so for me right this is my company
this is my next move
so I will be connecting Claude to this
something called sentry
is a error logging applications yeah
so to show you all what is a sentry right
is something like this
so he will log down all my like production
or staging unexpected areas
so all these sometimes I need to go in
and then see what's the issue here
and then I need to guess how I can fix this bug
so it's very hard to trace all these thing
so with this Sentry MCP right
so I can just ask Claude to help me just look at
this log and then give me what's the result
to help me resolve this bug
so I don't need to guess I don't need to wait ya
cause sometimes the bug is like very hidden
very deep
so I can't really solve in minutes or hours
so with Claude
then she can help me to solve maybe within 30 minutes
etcetera
yeah so below table is like the before and after
before we are hunting the logs and metrics and
see what's the bug
then we try to try to fix the bug
cause we need to guess mah
then lastly we verify whether the fix is work or not
then after that if I connect to MCP
then Claude will do everything for me
I just need to verify their changes
so lastly
why we move cause initially we are using cursor
but then after that we move to Claude
so understand that Claude and cursor actually
they behave quite similar
but in the end
we still choosing Claude for our team is because of
we are product based company
so our product logic are very customized and heavy
so in the end of the day
we choose quality over speed
so here are some metric that differentiate
the different between cursor and Claude
so just to summary what's the difference right
is that
for cursor whenever we try to prompt the AI right
so they will just like put everything inside the chat
and then whenever if you
if your feature is like very big right
then he will get chat population is like
he fit too many thing into the chat
then in the end of the day
he on self loss already
so he give you like very bad result but for Claude
he do different is that cause he will like
create a lot of sub agents for different task
so after the sub agent he complete right
then he will get the result
and send back to the main agent
so he only get what he needs
it's not the whole chunk of code or question
etcetera ya so this is the different
main different between current
and Claude but the drawback is
Claude has slower response
but I think it's smarter
it takes longer to process
but the result logic is
I think more accurate than cursor
yeah but if to do something like quite small one
then I think cursor definitely is better one
cause it has like a autocomplete
and nearly instant response compared to Claude
then I think should be that's all right okay
thank you all do you have any questions
yeah
thank you for the talk
sure I have several question about first question
first regarding the CLAUDE.md
what is the content that you primarily include in it
do you put like the how
is the architecture of the back end
or anything like that
yes correct so we do include like what so firstly
I need to describe what is my apps so like for example
my apps is a HRM
S so what module we have
and how many log in portal is there
for example mobile like web
maybe our back end management system etcetera
we have different portals to log in
so that's my first layer of
the details cause I need to list down first
so that they understand what is the different law
importers then from there
we have different rules for each portal
then after that
I list down the code structure and also logic within
so does it also like describe like
if I want to implement a new feature over there
like does the CLAUDE.md by itself already told like
oh what you have to follow this standard to do this
do that
or it got like reference to other files or what's not
ya it okay
so it does reference to other files
like the skill I show here
ya this one so like for example
I want to do like
maybe something re related to attendance
so you will come here and find
what are the trigger keyword here
cause I will store the keyword inside this SKILL.md
then whenever I do something like
I want to update my attendance
clocking out something like that
then he will try to find this file
then he will get the knowledge there
then he start doing the feature
and also about the skills
I noticed that you mainly like
separate each of the skill based on like feature right
the modules like
for
example attendance is one of the skill
and then maybe the claims is another skill
I also got do like skills for my company
me as well but right now
because I also am getting just getting started
and how I create this skill is actually like
make it like one skill for one kind of the
application layer for example
I want to do database migration one skill
database seeding
one skill or if you want to create a new API
one skill for that so I mainly want to know like
what are the
like how you come up with the decision to like
separate the skill based on the module and then
how it eventually lead to making this decision
separate it based on the module okay
understand your question so basically
why we split into like different report here right
is because of the product logic
cause our product logic
cause I need some place to store my product logic
what and the code structure is like quite different
like for each of the module
the expected code is different
expected code structure is different
so ya to us ya
so that's why I need a separate modules here
to store the different code structure ya
like for example different log in portals
we have different code standard also for example
our back end one
cause it's mainly used by our people only
so we just like do very basic code standard only
it's just like one time one 1 chunk big
one big chunk of code then just leave it
cause we not really maintaining that part mah
it's only for our own use
but if it's the main app right
then like we have like OOP
that kind we structure in OOP way etcetera
so that's the reason why I separate into like
by module oh
I see ya so each of the module
basically in maybe inside the skill and d
or maybe the reference file that it includes
or got mention like each of the module
how should the agent like quote out
what is the pros procedure that you should follow
yes ya something along the line
I understand another question
you use the superpower what
the one the plug in right
have you ever like run it
because it seems like it does a lot of thing
does it like if you ever run into the
oh never
cause this one is sponsored by my company 1
so I don't care about the token
ya huh I think the max 1 already ya
so I don't care about tokens
ya so I totally don't care about tokens
oh for me I
don't have that concern
cause it's free 1 and normally I run like 2
3 chat in parallel then ya that's why ya
Maybe in Claude documentation
the this one supposed to be the slash limit right
yeah
okay ya
you continue first and then
does the team
continue to extend the context of the limit
oh accuracy
yes correct ya
this one I keep many yeah
but I will maintaining the code structure
cause to me the different skill
I also keep maintaining for example
my code auditor
I also keep maintaining it cause I need
we need rules to make it accurate mah
so maybe something like
have something different happens
the rules is not
definitely the rules is not perfect one mah
so
I need to keep maintaining to make sure it's correct
it's accurate so this one we have to the
my team have to maintaining this one
like whenever whatever thing we add in right
so we need to add to here also
so this one should not be
have any stale information right
yes ya and this solve a lot of hmm
because this one
initially it need to load into the CLAUDE.md right
but then if for us the pro user
not the max user
I think this one is not that possible for pro user
right ya
this one I not too sure
cause we started with max and then next one is
ya I see there's a lot of
AI usage here then
what's the accuracy like how often's
this one the product is in production right
yes and then how often the product face like AI bugs
okay
so this one definitely we still got local test 1
so we have like before we ship to production
we have our QA team
etcetera to make sure the AI code is workable one ya
so we do have like different production
so first we in our team
we load our features to staging first
then in staging environment
we test everything and make sure it's good
then only we ship to production
so definitely AI is not perfect
so sometimes it still have some issue
but it's a tools that
to help us to cut down the development time yeah
so definitely it's still making mistake
so that's why I still need to maintain this
permanent context file ya
so actually my question is not like that
it's very professional
because since I'm not a software engineer
but I just want to pass because I also trying to see
because I also got to do these skills every
and also the AGENTS.md
I just want to ask
have you have explored other agents
for example the Codex
because the Codex have Codex
that there is a Codex also
then Codex also using this
and AGENTS.md and also SKILL.md
have you comparing like which one is more better
like this one
we actually currently we testing Codex also
but we just started last week
so we also not sure
but at first we start from cursor mah
so I can just now
I was showing the difference between cursor and Claude
so after in the end of the day we choose Claude
but now we trying Codex also
so we still not sure whether we switch there or not
but ya we still testing ya
so I also not sure what's the difference yet ya
but I have friends using Codex also
they say it's quite power than Claude
but I also not sure ya still testing ya because I
the quality is also more better than the Claude
but I think it's not because of the accuracy
maybe it's because of the value
because the token
you say for the Codex is more cheaper than the Claude
ya the Claude is like
for example 1 million token there is a $17 for Claude
but maybe for Codex is only $6
so maybe it's more viable
so that's why Codex is more viable
this one so
this one third to 15 oh
and the next question is for this particular context
right
so you are attending this
ya correct ya correct ya correct
so I also do have a rules here to say like
if they're trying to add some new logic right
then they will automatically check whether or not this
logic should be inserted into this markdown file ya
so that's where
AI also help us to maintaining this markdown file
ya so that's why it's getting very big
I think this permanent context
you cannot separate like for example
different parts of the permanent one contacts
that's all you only can
create all those room inside one farm ya correct cause
this one is basically like storing the general one mah
so I don't want woah
store like general inside the different skill markdown
cause maybe like if they never trigger that skill
then my roots
then cannot work already
ya so
that's why I just put all the general thing
inside this man
markdown file ya
hey that's a good question oh
ha yeah but
how around how many lines
like three two
three hundreds
I think more than that
the best practice is 200 lines ya
but we over the limit over
the limit already it's very a lot but
something I Learned recently
is I
still keep my CLAUDE.md 2 hundred line below 200 then
I do reference oh
so it's like when I say like may
maybe
there's a block about my architecture or something
right then I say like
load then the path to that
the relative path from the project folder
let's say like
docs slash arteca AR architecture dot MD
when then maybe like the keyword
like when to load this on demand oh
something like that I do that also
but I never separate the general 1
I also not sure whether this one is
but so far it's working okay
so that's why I never touch
but it's a very huge file ya
then I guess the trade off is because like
this file will load every single time
when you open a new session
no actually he
I don't know how he read also leh
it says that whenever I start my editor
then he have all these thing in background already
ya so
the I mean like when you start a Claude Code
if not wrong it will always load this file
because it's permanent contact yeah
correct yeah
so then it always load that 700 lines yeah
so maybe the token usage is more ya
but I don't care company one ya company sponsor one
so I don't care ya but ya
I think maybe can do that
cause now I also separate into all these
like different but ya
but I just ya I lazy to separate them
ya why your company decide to like try out Codex
cause they just like what
Peng say just now they say that token is
cause I think currently we hit
I'm not sure how much already
but quite expensive on our Claude Code ya
I think over few thousand
but it's cheaper than an engineer
so we decide to cut down the cost
that's why we trying to test out Codex ya
it still matters it still matters ya
1 one tool that recently ex company
ex company is using it
is called Graphify
and then I kind of like research what is the
purpose of Graphify it is like
cache the entire bundle file or context
then that's why every time you open
the VS Code right
it will directly already cached it there
it's something so
if you reading the context of the article
from the cache
so if you not use the proper usage to read again
on the phone
ya I think it's a skill because I because I saw the ya
there's a /graphify command so I think it's a skill
maybe I can
maybe I can look into this
also
I'm curious about your team
because there seems a lot of
the markdown file to maintain
so does it mean the team switch toward
to maintaining the markdown file
so like
what
I think just now Jun Wei asked a similar question
so I
did insert the rules into my markdown file already
so whenever they try to insert like new logics or what
right
then they will self-assert what's the related logic
then they will self-maintain the skill within
the markdown file ya
so I actually put a rules inside the markdown file to
check in every check section so if there is any new
logic added in while I running the code auditor
right
then he will help me to maintain the markdown file
which mean the
full team share the same skills and yes
correct ya this in our report
then I think this is the next month topic - Graphify
so ya any other questions