a good evening everyone
I'm Soh Jun Wei and first of all
thank you all for joining today's talk
and especially thank you to Hui Ming for hosting today
for hosting this event
so that I have the opportunity to share what
I have Learned when building up an application
so the topic today for me is AI for everyday friction
is essentially about
building a personal experience agent with
Hermes also using the MCP
this is not like about like to advertise like the
finance app or to like
especially on the AI workflow or something like that
it's more like sharing my experience
at the entire journey in like
building out this entire product
so let us just jump into it
so
for this one I will start out with explaining
I got this idea to like build this thing out
so we
I think we can all agree that
recording expense is a good habit
because you can know like where your money is going
where
did you spend all your like money at
but then NPS
before that I actually always been using a app
called Fortune City to record my expenses
it is actually a good application because it gamis
gamifies the experience like
at the same time I record the expense
I also like building out a city from it
but then eventually
I have been using it for already few years
and it eventually like it getting feel a little bit
tiresome a little bit of troublesome like you
because like
you have to open the app and then key in manually
thing by yourself and then yeah
especially if you have a like older model phone or the
your phone is not
like the gaming phone or something like that
then opening at the app
even opening the app will take like
a few seconds to do it
then you can imagine like situation
like when you are eating out with
other people
other people and then they after they check out
then you got the receipt and everything
everyone want to leave already but then you
suddenly you need to like ex
record the expense right
then you have to go through all these step
but everyone already go
so you like feel a kind of awkward because like
you want you want to record the expenses
and everyone is already want to leave already
and then maybe you can say oh
maybe I will just record it later
but of course there will be cases
where you forget to record the expenses
so this is why I feel like
maybe there is some easier way for me to like
record my expense for this typical use case
so the enemy here is not the expense checking
app is not to say like the checking app is not
good or anything it's actually very good
it gamifies the experience but the enemy is friction
basically you have to go through these little steps
it all it all builds up to like a frust
frustration and keep me from
keep using it something like that
so what if let's say this is
what I imagine
what if the input can be made to be more effortless
make it very easy for me to record a expense
first of all the basic idea is the text input
something like if let's say I just simple
very simple phrase like lunch
5.5 then it immediately the a
agent will know or no you are talking about
or you want to add a expense record
your lunch and 5.5 Malaysian ringgit
and then it will just store it entirely
the entire record in the database or even
in some cases maybe the expense is not so easy
maybe it needs you do some arithmetic
some calculation maybe like one time
10 ringgit plus something
plus something and maybe you got your tax again
maybe 6% tax
you also need to calculate that kind of stuff
maybe in
you need to use calculator
if let's say you are just using a
regular expense checking app
but then in this case maybe I can just state it out
and then the AI agent will do all the calculation
and then record it in the database
or even better
all of these I can just use a voice message
I just record like user I just say or
dinner 10.5 + 3.5 something like that
and then the AI agent will be able to like
and then just record in the database or even better
right you got the receipt
you got the receipt
I just take a photo of the receipt and say nothing else
then the AI agent will directly create the record
and add the attachment of the
receipt to this particular record
so this is idea that I try to build
earlier on and so right
so more specific on the implementation
so it basically will be designed like this
so previously
at the
with the idea that at that time also quite popular
the OpenClaw the OpenClaw
and then also the Hermes agent is quite popular at the
at the time also
I'm also trying to explore about that
so I saw
so it is convenient
so this idea and then I think
maybe that one entire system can be top of that
or open claw and the Hermes agent
so that one we will
we will use the Telegram as the primary platform to
like
have send my message through
and then
the AI will basically do the category detection
and then it extract the necessary information
text all of that
and then all of that will be saved to the database
saved to the database and then all of the
records will be visible in the dashboard
so the agent will not only be just chatting with
me like that
it will actually perform the real action
through the use of tools and that is why
we will have to use
MCP which I chose in this particular use case
for this one I will quickly demo a little bit
like
what I have built over the case and true demo
I will just show
one is the Telegram and the second is the dashboard
so if you can see my telegram over here
this is how I use the telegram right now
I have used it for quite like a month already
so like I buy some
snacks and then have some voice messages
you see you can see it
records all of into the database using the MCP
today my chat GPT got expired so I
have to subscribe again and then have some
voice message I see if all of you can hear
okay
something like this so
you just extract the information required
and then just
record it into the database
and also like photo of receipt right
photo of receipt like this
go to my news
buy some breakfast and then it will just
get all of this and then record it into and then
initially when I build this
it is just a AI agent
the telegram something like that
but then I figure out
the is let's say it have mistake or I have to like
I mean I prefer to manually edit this entire myself
right so
I eventually I also need the custom control
manual control
and that's why I also use AI to build out a dashboard
that which connect to the SQLite database
and then it come out of for the entrance
it basically got a dashboard something like this
so like
this month expenses all the category
all the charts and all the stuff
and then you can see over here
record expenses
like something like this and then like
for example
if let's say I have uploaded the
receipt right
it can be it can be attached over here
so I can see the receipt oh
like this
so the receipt just now is all attached in here alright
so this is the demo flow
so let touch a bit about the entire architecture
like of this action and build out of
so from over here from us
user side right we have like text mes text message
we have a voice input
speech input and also it can also be a receipt photo
and all of these will be sent through the Telegram
platform although
there is also other platform that we can set up of
like WhatsApp or anything
and then all of this infrastructure
I host it inside the Oracle Cloud actually
Oracle Cloud is quite generous
I they got provide a virtual private server service
I for free and the resource provided generous
so if you need something hosted like 24 hour
you can check that out
so all of this is inside the Oracle Cloud and then in
inside a Docker container
primarily built on top of the
Hermes Agent container
then I just add some of my personal dashboard inside it
and then yes this is the primary Hermes agent
all of the messages from Telegram will go through it
and then for the speech to text
Hermes agent actually support several options
like for example the whisper model hosted locally
but then because
those AI models will need some resources
so for my case
it will only be limited to whisper small model
which can be quite inaccurate
at the same time Hermes agent support the Groq
free API for the large model
so actually quite nice
the rate limit is quite hard to free
the free limit is quite rich
so it's
enough for my use case
and for the model that I use
I primarily use the open router
open router
I choose the Qwen 3.5 27B for the primary reasoning
it needs to charge money for that
one needs to charge money
it's pay as you go usage
but right now haven't exceed like 10 USD
something like that so up until now
so it can be considered quite cheap
maybe a message only 0.01 cent
something like that and for the receipt photo
you need to pass the image so it will
the open router will automatically
use the Gemini Flash Vision model
then we have the UH2 execution layer
this one is the MCP that is also developed for it
because alright have this agent
it reads the message
and then it have to perform the insert to the database
but then for inserting to the database
if let I also don't want it to like
always like
generate the SQL and then insert it by itself
every time because that one
it maybe if
let's say
I clear the session and then next time it don't know
don't know it generate the SQL
or maybe it download some tool
and then insert the database
so it's very unpredictable
so I have to create a MCP and then have
provide some tools for it to correctly insert the data
to the database
that one I can
I will elaborate in the following slides
and then the database is SQLite
and then this one to
store the images
is basically a folder inside the Docker container
and then lastly I have a dashboard
the admin interface using the next JS
yes so this one basically the topic just now
many people when they like
set up their Hermes or maybe the open claw agent
they will just think like
and may maybe they will just eat like
I just directly prompt it like oh
I want to save this thing
this help me to save this thing
help me to send that
thing and something like that
so that one is okay to use but then it will break
also you have to also deal with the agent being
unpredictable at times
because LLM by itself is a AI model
it is unpredictable so you cannot expect like
oh thing you will do the things the same way
even if you like create a skill to it
there is always some certain degree of the
unpredictability in it
so if let's say you just use the prompt
if you have to like reexplain the always repeatedly
there is a chance of it being a inconsistent there
also at the same time it will use more token also
and then if let's say
because I cannot just keep the session
keep going like that
the session eventually it will have to like
either compact or I have to clear out the session
and then it will just magically forget from it
be earlier before
and also the may invent the process by itself
maybe invent the process and then you
feel that one is not what I
what I want you
ask it to freeze and then there's more token used
ya so this is why I choose to like develop a MCP
is actually that MCP will show how is the
MCP is actually in the next slide
but it's actually you can think of it like API
but more suitable for the AI
it actually like on top of the
because you it be it also got endpoints
it's actually called tools over here
but it's actually like API endpoints but
you also code the logic behind every endpoint
but then on top of every point and point
you also add like a description
like a for the AI
like explaining how you would use this tool
what is the input schema
and then what is the output will be formatted
like kind of like that so by using MCP
MCP
it will provide with name tools
required fields valid categories validation rules
predictable outputs and also it
will be reusable
so this MCP like a API server
I can just throw it everywhere
the agent also can use the MCP
if let's say one day I decided to go back
claw or something like that
this MCP can also be applied to it
so the core message is that
MCP will reduce your guess work
guess work
by giving the agent a more well defined tool boundary
so a little bit you can see on this MCP so
you can see it almost like a API like
for example this app expense tool over here
you also provide it with a amount
a category which is a define of the category
you are allowed to pass in
and also the description
the date and also additional remarks have to
and also a calculate 2 over here
a little bit about this calculator because like
when AI do the math
it will sometimes it will get wrongly
I have no experience with it before
when I tell it like
the food plus the beverage
then it come out with the wrong number
I when I try to calculate it myself
and so figure it out
right now maybe best way is let him it to like
every time you have to do some calculation
call this function don't calculate it by yourself
okay so it's ya so basically
this MCP also by AI
I just tell the AI
what I need for and develop it as a AI as a MCP server
and then it just come all up
all of this
it's basically developed with Node.js
so this one
the main take away is that you
when you develop an application
you have to like split it by the two parts
one is the fuzzy input fuzzy input is like
for example natural language like
the Wu Chan Wei pan
that one that one is a fuzzy input that is not
always be the case for the computer so that one
for AI they will they perform the best in it
but like
inserting the record into the database and everything
for is deterministic
behaviour and that one is best performed by AI
but no not by AI by tools like
we define the logic like at the
using the MCP or using CLI
everything like that so for fuzzy input
we use AI for
hard rules like money validation and calculation
we define tools for the AI to use
that one is the best scenario
which I think
and then this one is basically more like
what I feel after like develop of this stuff
like there is always a feel feeling like
AI is going to replace us right
but then my right now my
thought on this is actually AI will not
remove developers
but if we are undergoing transformation
we have to change like what our primary
daily job as a developer is
you with using AI
it changes what we have to focus on
previously
we always do the manual coding and everything right
and we have to code everything by ourselves
then we got like Copilot it auto complete
just tap
and then everything
and right now the AI already help us to like
I just prompt the AI it just help us to code
out all of this stuff
so right now I think our
responsibility will have a little bit of the shift
maybe previously
we do 20% of the design and then 80% of like
coding out the thing that we want to build
but right now maybe we have to shift it
more like a 80% of designing and dis
deciding on what we have to build up
and then tell the AI to build
to code it out and then we verify the result ourselves
so we move more like
from a coder to become a orchestrator of the AI
and then to become a architect some
that is what I thought
a normal we
a normal
regular AI user ask the AI to solve the problem
but we as a developer
will go and design how AI
is allowed to solve the problem at the hand to
solve problem at hand
we cannot let it like go wild or do
whatever it need because
AI cannot see the picture that we
can see AI you will just like
or you tell me what to do
I will do whatever it takes to reach that
goal that you give me
so we have to give it
like the constraint and the restrictions that is to
like
achieve what we
so we don't just code
we design how the AI is allowed to act
so basically this is the
part where we have to identify which part of it is
like a fuzzy input
and which part is a deterministic act
deterministic action
when we are developing a AI application
we cannot just entirely depend everything
throw to AI and let AI expect AI to do the stuff to us
we have to know like
oh which one
which one of the job is actually best performed by AI
and which part of it is best performed by
the set of rule
predefined rules which is deterministic
like
natural language understanding
or voice or messy phrasing
and also the receipt interpretation
all of these is fuzzy input
and that one is what the AI do best
but then for deterministic action like
I have to like from the message
like Wu Chan is basically categorize
food and then maybe like a petrol and everything
that one is categorized as transport
that one category validation is validation
not categorization
if categorization is
still the fuzzy input best performed by AI
but then if
let's say
I only have a limited amount of the category that I
define the database can have
that one is deterministic and has to be set
the rules and also text and calculation
we have used tools for that data validation database
right summary and also attachment handling
all of these best to have a predefined set of rules
we don't want the AI to be like
oh for right now or maybe it has one
it just generate a sequel
by itself to insert database later in the next
time when you like clear the session
it just somehow come up with
it called a entire what
the framework for you to insert into the database
or something like that one is very unpredictable
and we don't want that in our AI application
so we have a little bit of like mention here
previously I
have also discussed with Hui Min
and we discuss on whether we should use
MCP or CLI and the core message
the way is I think like that is
how much less work do we want to lift to the AI
if let's say CLI is like
just in the terminal
and then AI will just generate the command inside the
of the terminal right
so if let's say for my use case over here
like the expense checking application at the end
if let's say I have
I develop the entire tool set inside the CLI
I also need to a guideline for the AI to understand
or how do I use this command
unless it's a very popular command
a Git command or maybe like the one in Linux
all of that one me
AI is already has been assisted for a long time
AI probably very familiar with it
that one is no problem to use the CLI
the C L I is the
a I is already trained of
on many of the C L I command
so for those popular commands
AI will have no problem working with it
but let's say if I have developed a custom tool set
and then I also need to attach like oh
you need to call this
tool when you want to do what thing
maybe what
are the inputs arguments that you have to pass in
what shape what kind of the input is allowed to have
and then also when during the error
it will need to return the error message
then the error message will also need to be
properly formatted for the AI
to understand or what goes wrong
and also what output structure the AI needs
what output the AI has to expect
when the 2 call is success
is success
so if let's say I have to build all of this thing
actually the will be still be MCP
because MCP
you call the tool and then it also will list out like
or this endpoint this tool
we'll
what did the description will describe
or when will you should be calling this tool
and then what are the input arguments
what what's schema you
we will have and also the output
the output structure that will be returned to the AI
so this is the take away
so basically when deciding or whether to MCP or CLI
you can you still can use CLI if let's say
the operation not don't have to be so like
well defined something like that
so of course
the application is still far from perfect
there is still some areas of improvement
for example like for the to text
like we
like with the text right
you know I have a 6% I
just
say Liu Liupasien
and then you will add liupasien
and then it will calculate it like a 6.8% or 68%
something like that
and then also for the receipt
the
sometimes I just
maybe in the lunch
I just say lunch
5.5 ringgit and then
for the dinner I just upload a receipt
and then
if you think that receipt is actually the lunch receipt
and then just tell me that
the that the
maybe you want to attach the receipt
and then that is also the tax and calculation error
but then
this one area is still going to be improved
and because of the time I rush a bit
this is the next
step improvement
a little bit of introduce
this one is actually a personality that I trying to
like add into the
over here
this one
call Auria and then basically the character
I just generally using the chat GPT
like
it will be a character to inside the
inside this
finance checking
assistant to give it a more of an Auria
and then there is still many improvements to be done
in the later phase
so okay
so call to conclude this about ppt
so basically
we don't have
to always find a huge AI project
idea to get started to using the AI
we can just observe from our life like oh
maybe we got some friction doing this and doing that
we just start from small fiction and then try to see
how AI can actually help us to
improve the workflow and everything
and use AI for fuzzy understanding
part of the application
use tool for deterministic action
and then we as developers
we will design the boundary
for what the AI is allowed to use
the I think the I believe
I strongly believe this is the correct way to
for us developers to use the AI
so I think that's all for today
thank you everyone
so the Q&A session so any questions
maybe I go first so
actually
I very curious on the part that you say
you are integrating the Telegram with the
with the Hermes AI agent actually
because I was
getting from you also
because I saw you are doing the AI budget tracking
so actually I also wonder that
is it I also can do it so I so
I think this week I just try it
during my time to develop my own
AI budget tracking itself also
but my agent is actually using the cloud
the desktop and then I building the connector to the
to my own
MCP server
to and then do it like you like a API endpoint
there's a add expenses
all those inside my MCP server endpoint
so I just configure your RL inside the cloud desktop
to do the connection so I just
very curious about how Hermes
can work with the Telegram actually
it's like this if let's say for Hermes
it is hosted like 24 hours on my
Docker container inside my virtual private server
and when setting up the Hermes agent
it will essentially ask you for the channel
they call it Channel and then for it
you will like ask for the
Telegram token that will you
will get when you set up the Telegram bot
and then how it is actually doing getting the message
it he it is doing polling
it's like oh
like for over some time
for some interval of time
it will go hit the telegram or do or do
this bot have new in or no
then I wait for like few seconds
and then I just ask again
or how
do it have like a new message coming in
no then repeat rinse and repeat oh
I see so like a like a break off special
job if you run it like every
minute or every single every period we call this
they regret to see there is a any new
message coming in
then that one inside the Hermes or the OpenClaw they
this concept they call they
call it they have a service for it
they call it the gateway
if you see the term gateway essentially means this
channel service message and also some on top of other
things
like they got the job
the heartbeat and everything like that I see okay
thank okay
I think that's the question for me okay
thank you very good question
any other questions
I have a quick one I have a quick one I
does it support WhatsApp
for Hermes I'm not sure
but OpenClaw
so far OpenClaw is support most of the
channel even Line everything like that for Hermes
I'm not sure yes
most oh
okay it
supports her WhatsApp
but it will take a more steps for it to configure
because Telegram you just
you just prompt a bot and then it's
the bot is just appear already oh
okay so actually Telegram is provide the token
so is it the WhatsApp
also provide the token for us to connect
to get the data from the WhatsApp
I think so I haven't sent yes
I think I have cause I did something similar also
oh
so basically like that
so no more questions oh
I have one more like
do you plan to open source this project
I eventually I plan actually got
plan to upload it to my personal GitHub
after I have added the personality inside
like update a little bit
fix a thing here and there
and then I will upload it to my GitLab
and then I plan to also like make a Docker container
so I
just one command and everything
including the dashboard will be set up like that
but recently with the work so
less time for me to work on this project
then once you open source it yeah
I will I will inform it the group
I will also it on the
personal profile
something like that okay
any other questions no other question can
you go back to the there's one NPS
slide regarding
the
token
the whisper
something long whisper and short whisper
because you mention that there's a whisper large
may I know the whisper large
it is like let's say
because just now I noticed the telegram
whisper message is around like
8 seconds
the whisper large is it like referring
can
your voice message can like one minute or something
I think the main like the model
because the whisper model is actually from open AI
open AI they release the open source
voice
to text yes
voice to speech to text
speech to text model and the difference
be small and large is essentially like the models like
UH27B UHHUNDREDB
something like the how accurate it will effect how
accurate the output of the
speech to text functionality like for example
if let's say I my voice is a little bit unclear
maybe on the small model it will come out
incorrect
but on the large model because it trained on more
it got more parameters
and then it will just come out more correct
the
is the main difference is the accuracy of the result
but at the same time it more resource
compute resource how about the daily usage limit
that one is the usage limit is based on how much
that is produced in the
in the voice message and then it converts to text
that is the limit right
it's like this if you host
you decided to host the whisper model yourself
there is no limit the limit is your
computer then for this Groq free API
I think like one day I it have like 200 it
calculate based on request
you like you hit how many request and then
is it request or I think seconds
how
the total length of the voice you send in the day
for it to process
that's all from me anymore okay
so quick question
the you are using Groq free API or Whisper
in initially I you host the whisper model
locally on the virtual private server
but on it only can host up until the model
and then the result is a little bit inaccurate
then I see oh
it also provide the Groq free API
this Groq free API is actually also a service provider
and it hosts the whisper model also
but it only provides whisper large
so after changing to it the
accuracy is increased oh okay
any other question if not ya
I think that's all thank you
Jun Wei okay
thank you everyone for listening