hi everyone my name is Jia Wen
tonight I want to share how I track my spending
every lunch here costs around 15 ringgit
and some days it goes up to 20 ringgit
I used to record everything in a spreadsheet
almost 80 percent of my entries were wrong
so I decided to write a small program
it started as a weekend software project
the agent reads my receipts from Telegram
then it stores every record in a database
the database runs on my old laptop at home
I use Claude to extract the amounts
actually I write most of the code with Claude Code
the whole flow is wired up through MCP
the MCP server exposes three simple tools
all the source code is on GitHub
the skill instructions live in a SKILL.md file
without a network connection nothing syncs
so I added an offline queue for the data
every month it generates a short video summary
the video shows where my money actually went
last month food was 40 percent of everything
transport was another 25 percent
that information completely changed my habits
I cut my coffee budget by 100 ringgit
the program now runs every single night
it posts the summary back to Telegram
my friends asked if the software is hard to maintain
honestly Claude Code does most of the maintenance
thank you and find me on GitHub if you want the code